http://www.sumoservices.com/privacy-policy

Update Preferences
Privacy PolicyThe following Privacy Policy is issued by the SUMO Services Ltd, on behalf of the SUMO Group of Companies (‘SUMO’).SUMO is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and meeting our obligations under the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016 (GDPR) 2018 and the UK Data Protection Act 1998.For the purpose of the GDPR 2018, the data controller is SUMO Services Ltd and our data protection representatives can be contacted at data.protection@sumoservices.comWhat personal data do we collectThe GDPR classes your name as personal data. Your email address, if it includes your name, is also classed as personal data.  All personal data that we collect about you will be recorded, used, and protected by us in accordance with applicable data protection legislation and this privacy policy.  The personal data we process includes: -Identity Data - which includes title, first name, last name, and username.Contact Data - which includes billing address, site address, email address and telephone numbers.Financial Data - which includes bank account details for our suppliers.Transaction Data - which includes details about payments to and from you and other details of services you have purchased from us.Usage Data - which includes information about how you use our website, products and services.Marketing and Communications Data - which includes your preferences in receiving marketing information from us.Where do we collect your data?We may collect and process personal data from you as follows: -Directly from yourself when you complete a form, use our website or send us correspondence by email, letter or telephone. This includes data when you: -Request a quotationSubscribe to our marketingParticipate in a surveyProvide feedback on a service or experienceHow do we use your personal data?We will use your data in the following ways: -To meet our contractual obligations to you when you commission a service.  This includes communicating with you about your commission, both before and after the service is provided.To update you on any services linked to (or similar to) your past requests or commissions, as well as services you have expressed an interest in.To respond to any correspondence, you send to us.To comply with any applicable law and regulation.In accordance with our legitimate interests in protecting SUMO's legitimate business interests and legal rights, including but not limited to, use in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory and investigative purposes (including disclosure of such information in connection with legal process or litigation).To respond to any comments or complaints we may receive from you, and/or in accordance with our legitimate interests including to investigate any complaints received from you or from others, about our website or our products or services.We may use information you provide to personalise (i) our communications to you; (ii) our website; and (iii) products or services for you.To monitor use of our websites and online services. We may use your information to help us check, improve and protect our products, content, services and websites, both online and offline.Marketing communicationsWe may also send you direct marketing in relation to relevant products and services. Direct marketing will only be sent where you have given your consent to receive it, or (where this is allowed) you have been given an opportunity to opt-out. You will continue to be able to opt-out of direct marketing at any time by following the instructions in the relevant communication, updating your preferences or by emailing data.protection@sumoservices.com at any time.
Update your preferences
Who do we share your data with, and why?Please be assured that we will never sell your data to third party organisations.  We may share your personal data with our group companies to process it for the purposes of inter-group administration and to deliver products or services where elements of these are provided by group companies other than those with which you have directly contracted.We may also share your personal data with the below third parties: -Our professional advisors such as our auditors and external legal and financial advisors.Marketing and communications agencies where they have agreed to process your personal data in line with this Privacy Notice.Market research companies.Our suppliers, business partners and sub-contractors.Search engine and web analytics.Personal data may be shared with government authorities and/or law enforcement officials if required for the purposes above, if mandated by law or if needed for the legal protection of our legitimate interests in compliance with applicable laws.Personal data may also be shared with third party service providers who will process it on behalf of SUMO for the purposes above. Such third parties include, but are not limited to, providers of website hosting, maintenance and credit checking.In the event that our business or any part of it is sold or integrated with another business, your details will be disclosed to our advisers and those of any prospective purchaser and will be passed to the new owners of the business.How do we protect your INFORMATION?We understand the concerns you may have about giving us your personal data.  We hold your data securely in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and with the General Data Protection Regulation from 25th May 2018 and your data is held on secure servers in the UK.How long do we hold your data?We continually review stored data and will not retain your data for any longer than necessary.  We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including satisfying any contractual, legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.We are also required to retain certain information as required by law or for as long as is reasonably necessary to meet regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our terms and conditions.Your rightsYou have many rights regarding your personal data: -You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data, clicking the unsubscribe button on any communication we have sent to you or by contacting us.Where you have consented to us using your personal data, you can withdraw that consent at any time.If the information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you can notify us and ask us to correct or supplement it.You also have the right, with some exceptions and qualifications, to ask us to provide a copy of any personal data we hold about you.If you wish to exercise any of these rights in relation to the personal data we hold about you, please contact data.protection@sumoservices.com or write to the Data Protection Officer, SUMO Group, Unit 8 Hayward Business centre, New Lane, Havant, Hampshire, PO9 2NL.Concerns and complaintsIf you have any concerns or complaints regarding our data processing approach in relation to your own data, please contact data.protection@sumoservices.com in the first instance. Your communication will be acknowledged and then responded to within 1 month.If you are not satisfied with the outcome you can raise your concern with the Information Commissioner’s Office. For information on how to contact them, visit www.ico.org.uk/concernsChanges to this Privacy NoticeWe keep our data protection notice under regular review. This privacy notice was last updated in May 2018. We may revise this policy at any time.
